http://www.jimmychoo.com/customer-services/privacy-policy.html

Search
Enter search text and submit search, or view filtered content in drop-down below. Use Tab to enter the drop-down content.
Sign in
Need assistance?
Go Back
Shipping to:
Search
Enter search text and submit search, or view filtered content in drop-down below. Use Tab to enter the drop-down content.
SCOPE AND CONSENT
This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") is applicable to us.jimmychoo.com (the "Website") and describes the ways in which information about users of the Website is collected, used, and disclosed when users visit the Website and interact with the services and features offered through the Website (including the online store).
The operator of the Website is J Choo USA, Inc. ("Jimmy Choo", "our", "we", or "us"), which is located at 11 West 42nd Street, Floor 27, New York, NY 10036.
As indicated in the General Terms and Conditions of Sale, Jimmy Choo manages the Website's online store, which involves managing activities such as processing orders, delivering products, and processing returns as well as other activities necessary to facilitate the sale of products via the Website. To perform these activities, Jimmy Choo may process users' information (including name, address, and credit card information).
By using the Website, each user consents to our collection, use, disclosure, retention, storage, and transfer of his/her information as described in this Privacy Policy, the Terms and Conditions of Use and Terms and Conditions of Sale (https://us.jimmychoo.com/en/customer-services/terms-and-conditions-of-sale.html).
This Privacy Policy applies solely to the Website and does not apply to other websites that users may be able to access via links on the Website and/or activities offered by third parties.
This information may be integrated with further personal information collected also in our stores.
The data controller of the Website is J. Choo Limited, with registered office at 10 Howick Place, London, SW1P 1GW United Kingdom (Company Registered Number: 03185783) ("Jimmy Choo", "we", or "us"). Jimmy Choo is part of Jimmy Choo Group Limited (the “Group”) which is part of the Capri Holdings Limited luxury fashion group.
COLLECTION OF DATA
A user can browse the Website without telling us who he/she is or revealing any personal information about himself/herself. If a user chooses to provide us with personal information (e.g., in connection with the use of the services and features offered through the Website), however, then he/she is no longer anonymous to us.
We collect the following types of information (collectively "Data") in order to provide users with the use of and access to the Website and/or the services and features offered through the Website as well as to help us personalize and improve users' experiences on the Website:
Information we collect automatically: the computer systems and processing programs used to operate the Website automatically log certain data during their normal operation. This data includes, but is not limited to, device ID or unique identifier, device type, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the Website, referring URL, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, standard web log information, and anonymous information collected through our use cookies and web beacons (collectively, "Surfing Data"). Some Surfing Data may allow us to identify users if the Surfing Data is associated with other data owned by third parties. Jimmy Choo collects Surfing Data in anonymous form exclusively for statistical purposes and for purposes of monitoring and enhancing the functioning of the Website and its content.
Information provided voluntarily by users: users may provide personal information to us voluntarily, such as when contacting us (e.g., via email), interacting with the Website's features, making requests for services offered through the Website, completing forms to access protected sections of the Website, and purchasing products through the online store. The personal information voluntarily provided by users may include, but is not limited to, name, gender, email address, phone number, address, financial information (such as credit card and/or bank account numbers), as well as shipping, billing, and other information that users provide to purchase products through the Website and any other personal information that we may ask users to provide to use our services.
COOKIES AND AUTOMATIC DATA COLLECTION TOOLS
The Website uses certain tools, such as cookies, to automatically collect Data. A cookie is a small text file that is used to store information on a user's Internet browser or a user's computer's hard drive when the user visits a website, such as the Website. A cookie does not contain information that identifies a person, but it allows for the linking of a user's computer to the information provided by the user on the Website (such as, for example, linking a user's IP address and other information about the user's experience on the Website to his/her preferences expressed while choosing services and purchasing products offered through the Website). Cookies are disseminated by servers and no one may gain access to information contained therein. The information stored in cookies is gathered directly and automatically by the Website and is processed in an aggregate and anonymous manner.
The use of cookies and other automatic data collection tools is necessary for the proper functioning of the Website and its services. In the event a user disables cookies, Jimmy Choo cannot ensure that all web pages of the Website will be displayed and/or that certain services will be supplied.
JIMMY CHOO uses the following types of cookies:
STRICTLY NECESSARY COOKIES
These cookies are essential in order to enable you to browse the Site. Without these cookies, services offered by the Site (such as use of the shopping bag or access to your order history) cannot be provided.
ANALYTICAL COOKIES
These cookies are used to measure and analyse how the visitors use the Site (for example site traffic, total sales through the Site, the pages visitors go to most often and pages from which the visitors get error messages) in order to continuously improve the Site and the shopping experiences through the Site. All information collected by these cookies are aggregate and in an anonymous form (even if pass onto third parties) and are not enable to identify you.
FUNCTIONALITY COOKIES
These cookies are not necessary for the functioning of the Site but allow the Site to remember the choices and/or the preferences (such as your username, language or the region you are located) in order to offer you some advanced, simplified and personalized features.
TARGETING AND ADVERTISING COOKIES
Targeting and advertising cookies may be used to deliver personalised advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests. These cookies may collect quite detailed information about your browsing habits through the Site, such as products you have clicked on or put in your shopping bag. These cookies allow us to personalise any direct marketing communication (i.e. email) or to limit the number of time you see and advertisement or to help us to measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. They also may enable us (or third-party advertising services we work with) to track the actions of users online over time and across different web sites or platforms to measure statistics of our marketing efforts, and to deliver electronic advertisements that may be more relevant to individual consumers and that will improve the consumer experience. We do not currently respond to web browser "do not track" signals or other mechanisms that provide a method to opt out of the collection of information across the networks of websites and online services in which we participate. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Policy. For more information about do not track, visit www.allaboutdnt.org.
THIRD PARTY COOKIES AND SOCIAL MEDIA ACCESS
Please note that if you share content from the Site through third parties websites (i.e. social networking websites) you may be sent cookies from these websites, and you activity on our Website becomes subject to the privacy policies of those other websites/services. JIMMY CHOO does not control the setting of such cookies and encourage you to refer to the relevant third parties website for more information about their cookies and how to manage them, as well as their privacy policies and how they handle information to which they gain access as a result of your decision to log into our Website using your social media credentials. You can, at any time, disable cookies or delete cookies already on your device by selecting the appropriate setting on your internet browser. Information on deleting or controlling cookies are available at www.AboutCookies.org. Please note that by deleting the Site cookies or disabling future cookies you may impede some functionalities of the Site or your possibility to interact with the Site.
DATA SUBMISSION
Users may be required to provide certain Data to us to create an account on the Website and to access the services and features offered through the Website, including the online store and the relevant e-commerce services. Failure to provide Data to us may prevent a user from accessing and using the services and features offered through the Website.
The provision of Data to us for marketing purposes is always voluntary and optional. In the event a user elects to not provide Data to us for marketing purposes, that choice will have no effect on the user's ability to use the services and features offered through the Website.
DATA TYPES COLLECTED
Information we collect about you:
when you sign up to our newsletter or updates;
when you enter competitions and prize draws;
when you register with the Website, by phone or by email, or provide personal information;
which you complete, or which we complete at your request in-store via a store card;
when you place an order on our Website;
if you ask us to keep in touch with you;
if you ask us to receive personalised online content such as targeted advertising;
if you complete a survey or send us feedback about our products, Websites or stores; or;
if you contact or correspond with us (for example, by phone, email or otherwise) to find out more about a product or our after sale care and support services, to report a problem with the Website or a product or for any other reason.
The personal information you give us may include your first and surname, title, gender, birthdate (day and month), email address, phone number, address, financial information (such as credit or debit card details), as well as shipping address, billing address, and any other information that you consider necessary to provide us with.
The information collected from you via our Website will be matched with personal information you may have given us in our stores. This is to help us ensure that the data we hold about you is kept accurate and up to date.
Information other Jimmy Choo Group members collect about you
This is information we receive about you when you make a purchase in one of our stores or concession stores if you have completed a store personal information card. These stores will also provide us with a record of your transaction.
Information we receive from other sources about you
We work closely with third parties, for example, business partners, sub-contractors for technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers and search information providers. If we receive information about you from them, we will always seek assurances that they are providing information to us in accordance with data protection laws and that they are transparent with you that they may share your data with us. We may use this information to update our records about you to keep them accurate.
USE OF DATA
Jimmy Choo may use Data for the following purposes:
PURPOSE
WHAT WE MAY USE
To improve your experience in our stores and on the Sites including: to track your activities on the Sites; to track clicks, purchases and conversion; to recognize your computer or device so that you are able to save your preferences and stay logged in to the Site without having to re-enter your online account credentials; to preserve the contents of your shopping cart and remind you if you have left items in it, or to remind you if you left the Sites without adding items to your cart; and to otherwise enhance, monitor and analyze our site usage.
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, demographic information, order history, transaction information, IP address, preferences, site usage information
To process and fulfil your requests for products and services, and to keep you informed about your requests or orders
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, payment information, transaction information
To administer and communicate with you about your account
Name, email address, zip code, date of birth, order history, preferences, gender, transaction information, site usage information
To better understand you, including in order to provide: personalized content, tailored offers, personalized messaging, and targeted advertising on and in connection with our Sites, services and products; and a personalized shopping experience
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, order history, IP address, preferences, transaction information, site usage information
To contact you (via postal mail, email, SMS or any other method you have elected) with promotional materials about Jimmy Choo and our Sites, services, products and select partners
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, preferences, demographic information, transaction information, site usage information
To contact you in connection with your relationship with us (such as via email in regards to your rating or review submissions)
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, preferences, site usage information
For market research and to review, better understand and improve our advertising and emails, merchandise selections, content, services, programs, customer service, business planning, online and offline operations and overall shopping experiences
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, order history, IP address, transaction information, site usage information
To enforce our terms and conditions, and to protect the security or integrity of the Sites, our customers and our business in general (such as protecting against illegal or fraudulent activity, or misuse including cyber-attacks)
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, payment information, order history, transaction information, IP address, site usage information
To set up and manage your online account (including, for example, to send password reminders or notifications to changes to your account details) and to process your communication and privacy preferences
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, payment information, order history, preferences, site usage information
To process product returns, replacements, repairs and alterations; to resolve product issues (e.g., sending replacement products); and other customer service related issues
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, payment information, order history, transaction information
To comply with legal requirements
Name, email address, postal address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, order history, payment information, site usage information
Furthermore, with a user's freely given consent, Jimmy Choo may also use Data to create individual or group profiles (user profiling) and for marketing purposes, notably to send to users-via newsletters, emails, or text messages-information and updates on Jimmy Choo products or initiatives, offers, exclusive sales, promotional campaigns, and events and shows organized by Jimmy Choo or in which Jimmy Choo takes part, including invitations to those events and shows. To opt-out of receiving marketing messages from us, see the User’s Choice sections below.
We do not share users' Data to third parties for their marketing purposes without users' explicit consent. We may combine users' Data with information we collect from other sources and use it to improve and personalize our advertising and marketing to users. We do not sell users’ data to any third parties.
STORING AND PROTECTING DATA
Data collected will be stored and processed via an electronic system owned and managed by ENTSERV SCHWEIZ GMBH (a DXC Technology company) (“DXC”) with its registered office address at Überlandstrasse 1, 8600 Dübendorf, Switzerland, a service company to the Jimmy Choo Group.
We protect users' Data by using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risk of loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access controls. Please understand, however, that no system is perfect or can guarantee that unauthorized access or theft might not occur.
We take steps to ensure that the Data we collect is accurate and up to date, and we provide users with the opportunity to update their information as specified in this Privacy Policy. To provide use with updated information, contact us at customercare.usa@jimmychoo.com.
DATA COMMUNICATION AND DISCLOSURE
Data will be accessible by Jimmy Choo personnel, including employees and external contractors.
We may also share users' Data with:
RECIPIENT/PURPOSE OF DISCLOSURE
WHAT WE MAY SHARE
To our service providers and suppliers who collect or use such information on our behalf (such as website or database hosting companies, address list hosting companies, email service providers, customer service providers, chat service providers, stylists, analytics companies, distribution companies, fulfilment companies, and other similar entities that help us to operate the Sites and Services and/or to provide functionality, content and services)
Name, email address, mailing address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, demographic information, order history, IP address, payment information, preferences, transaction information, site usage information
As necessary, if we believe that there has been a violation of the Site Terms and Conditions, or any other Site or company policy, or if we have reason to believe that our rights or property, or the rights or property of any third party, may be or have been harmed.
Name, email address, mailing address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, demographic information, order history, transaction information, IP address, payment information, preferences, site usage information
To provide information to and as required by local law enforcement agencies, other local government authorities, or otherwise required by law or to protect the rights and safety of our property, company and customers.
Name, email address, mailing address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, demographic information, order history, preferences, transaction information, IP address, payment information
On a case by case basis, in the event that Jimmy Choo or substantially all of its assets are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of an acquisition, merger, sale, consolidation, bankruptcy, liquidation or other similar corporate reorganization, where your information may be one of the transferred assets.
Name, email address, mailing address (including zip code), telephone number, date of birth, demographic information, order history, IP address, payment information, preferences, transaction information, site usage information
The aforementioned third parties that may receive users' Data will process that Data for the same purposes as specified above and in accordance with applicable law. Jimmy Choo will retain a list of the third parties with which Data is shared, which will be available upon request.
If users' Data will be used or disclosed for any purpose other than the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, they shall receive prior notification of such use or disclosure. Data will be transferred to Jimmy Choo Group companies located outside the United States or EEA only with a user's freely given consent.
THIRD PARTY WEBSITES
The website might, from time to time, contain links to third parties websites and the other companies websites belonging to the Group, which may have their own Privacy Policies. Jimmy Choo will not be responsible for these websites, the activities and practices that take place on these websites or the relevant associated Privacy Policies. This Privacy Policy is provided solely.
USERS' CHOICES
Users are entitled to obtain, at any time, a copy of their personal information and to have any inaccuracies corrected. Where appropriate, users may have their personal information deleted, corrected, amended, or completed. To do so, please or send an email to customercare.usa@jimmychoo.com, or write to us at J Choo USA, Inc., 11 West 42nd Street, Floor 27, New York, NY 10036
Users may revoke, at any time, consent to the delivery of commercial and promotional material via email by clicking the "unsubscribe" link in every commercial communication sent by Jimmy Choo and/or other companies of the Jimmy Choo Group.
CHILDREN'S INFORMATION
The Website is not directed to, nor do we knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13. If you become aware that your child or any child under your care has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us at J Choo USA, Inc., 11 West 42nd Street, Floor 27, New York, NY 10036 or send an email to customercare.usa@jimmychoo.com.
YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
Under California law, California residents have the right to request from JIMMY CHOO the names and addresses of third parties to whom we have disclosed personally identifiable information about you and whom we know or reasonably should know to have used such information for direct marketing purposes. For your own privacy and security, in our discretion we may require you to prove your identity before providing the requested information.
You also have the right to request that we delete personal information that we process about you, except we are not obligated to do so under certain circumstances, such as if we need to retain such data in order to comply with a legal obligation or to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.
To make such requests, please contact us at USprivacy@jimmychoo.com or call us at 1-800-913-4393
We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your rights.
BRAND PROTECTION
Jimmy Choo works with customs authorities, law enforcement and legal representatives globally in an effort to prevent the sale of counterfeit Jimmy Choo products, both online and offline. To avoid the risk of purchasing counterfeit products, it is best to buy only from an official Jimmy Choo e-commerce website, an official Jimmy Choo retail store, or an authorized department store, specialty retailer or e-tailer that you know to be reputable. To report counterfeits, please email brandprotection@capriholdings.com.
UPDATES
We will notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the amended terms on the Website. In the case of any changes that affect user rights, we will provide at least thirty (30) days’ notice before the effective date of the changes. If you have provided us with your email address, we will also notify you of material changes to this Privacy Policy that would affect your rights by sending an email at least thirty (30) days before the effective date of the changes to the email address you most recently provided to us. We encourage you to keep the email address you provide to us current, and to promptly notify us of any changes to your email address, so that you may receive any notices we send to you regarding material changes to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the new terms, you should stop using the Website, and if you are a registered user, you may cancel your account with us within the thirty (30) day period by contacting us at customercare.usa@jimmychoo.com. and you will not be bound by the new terms. Otherwise, continued use of the site after the effective date of changes constitutes acceptance of the new terms.
Please contact our customer care team customercare.usa@jimmychoo.com if you have any questions about our privacy statement.
This Privacy Policy was updated on 31st December 2019.
Need help? Dial Customer Care toll-free (+1)18778944126
